<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Proposals for raising money for the National Land-Bank</title>
            <author>Briscoe, John, fl. 1695.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 12 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A29549</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B4753</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R8972</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12381709</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12381709</idno>
            <idno type="VID">60790</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A29549)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 60790)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 909:15)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Proposals for raising money for the National Land-Bank</title>
                  <author>Briscoe, John, fl. 1695.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by John Darby ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1695]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
                  <note>Broadside.</note>
                  <note>Publication date taken from BM.</note>
                  <note>Included on p. [2]: An account of the value of the estates in the several counties subscribed towards the fund for a National Land-Bank from Thursday the 11th of June, to Saturday the 17th of August, 1695.</note>
                  <note>Signed at end: John Briscoe.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Land Bank (London, England)</term>
               <term>Broadsides</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:60790:1"/>
            <head>PROPOSALS for raiſing Money for the <hi>NATIONAL LAND-BANK.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>I Have been very often earneſtly importuned by divers Perſons, to permit them to ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribe a Sum of Money to the <hi>National Land-Bank,</hi> in lieu of Land, which I did not then think proper or convenient to accept of: But ſince the ſaid Bank is deſigned for a <hi>General and extenſive Good,</hi> and ſeveral Perſons ſtill renewing their Solicitations to ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribe Money to the ſaid Bank; that none therefore may be excluded from taking part of the many Advantages that will ariſe thereby; and in regard it may be a means to unite the Owners of Land and Money in point of Intereſt, it is thought neceſſary to receive Subſcripti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons for a <hi>Million</hi> of Money on the following Terms and Conditions, ſtill reſerving to my ſelf what I have yet to offer for raiſing any farther Fund of Money or Credit that may be needful for the ſaid Bank.</p>
            <p>That any Perſons may ſubſcribe what Sum of Money they pleaſe in the <hi>preſent Subſcription-Books,</hi> until the Value of <hi>one Million</hi> in Money ſhall be ſubſcribed.</p>
            <p>That every <hi>fifteen hundred Pounds</hi> in <hi>Money</hi> that ſhall be ſubſcribed, ſhall be eſteemed equal to <hi>two thouſand Pounds</hi> in <hi>Land,</hi> the ſame being the full Value for which ſuch <hi>Land</hi> may be en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaged, and ſhall have an <hi>equal Vote</hi> in all Elections with <hi>one hundred Pounds per annum,</hi> or two thouſand Pounds worth of Land, and in like proportion for a greater or leſs Sum.</p>
            <p>That the whole Million to be ſubſcribed ſhall be paid <hi>in ſpecie,</hi> in manner as is herein after appointed.</p>
            <p>That each Subſcriber, his Heirs, Executors, Adminiſtrators, or Aſſigns, ſhall pay to the <hi>Treaſurer</hi> or <hi>Treaſurers</hi> of the <hi>National Land-Bank,</hi> to be hereafter choſen, one tenth part of his or her ſaid Subſcription-Money on the 29th Day of <hi>September</hi> next, or within ten Days af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter; one other tenth part on the five and twentieth Day of <hi>December</hi> next, or within ten Days after; and the like tenth part on the five and twentieth Day of <hi>March</hi> th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n next following, or within ten Days after; and ſo to continue the like Paiments quarterly, upon the four moſt uſual Feaſt-days or Terms of the Year ſucceſſively, or within ten Days after each and every ſuch Feaſt-day or Days of Paiment, until all and every the ſaid tenth Pa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ts ſhall be paid to the <hi>Treaſurer</hi> or <hi>Treaſurers</hi> of the Bank in manner aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>That all and every the Subſcribers, their Executors, Adminiſtrators or Aſſigns, ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive from the Treaſurer or Treaſurers of the ſaid Bank, after the rate of 3 <hi>l. per cent. per annum,</hi> for all the Money they ſhall from time to time pay into the ſaid Bank, purſuant to their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> part of the Profi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s or the Bank: The ſaid 3 <hi>l. per cent. per annum</hi> to be paid them in two equal Paiments, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> upon the 25th Day of <hi>March,</hi> and 29th Day of <hi>September</hi> every Year.</p>
            <p>That each and every Subſcriber ſhall receive his or their Part or Propo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>tion of the Profits of the Bank for the whole Sum by them ſubſcribed, the ſame to be comp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ted from the time they ſhall pay their firſt tenth Part or quarterly Paiment.</p>
            <p>That if any Subſcriber ſhall fail to pay his firſt tenth Part or quarterly Paiment upon the 29th Day of <hi>September</hi> next, or within ten Days after, ſuch Subſcriber's Subſcription ſhall be void.</p>
            <p>☞ That the ſaid Bank may be a <hi>ſafe Repoſitory</hi> for the Money of all <hi>Widows</hi> and <hi>Orphans,</hi> it is thought ſit likewiſe to publiſh, That all ſuch Money of <hi>Widows</hi> or <hi>Orphans</hi> which ſhall not be ſubſcribed towards the raiſing the aforeſaid Sum of <hi>ten hundred thouſand Pounds,</hi> ſhall at any time (upon Application firſt to be made to the Directors) be received into the Bank, who will pay them after the rate of 3 <hi>l. per cent. per annum,</hi> for intereſt, and their Principal Money on Demand.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <date>7th <hi>Auguſt,</hi> 1695.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>John Briſcoe.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="postscript">
            <p>The Subſcription-Books lie open at <hi>Thomas Gooding,</hi> Sergeant at Law, his Chambers in <hi>Grays-Inn:</hi> At <hi>Philip Nev<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Eſq his Chambers, the ſecond Stair-caſe of the Paper-Buildings in the <hi>Inner-Temple:</hi> At <hi>Lawrence Braddon</hi> Eſq his Chambers, Number 4. the ſecond Stair<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſe in the New Square at <hi>Lincolns-Inn:</hi> At the Houſe of <hi>Robert Weſt</hi> Eſq the Corner of <hi>Buc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Humfry Hack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhaw</hi>'s in <hi>Lothbury</hi> near the <hi>Royal-Exchange:</hi> At Mr. <hi>Nicholas Hayward</hi> Publick Notary in <hi>Threadneedle-ſtreet</hi> behind the <hi>Royal-Exchange;</hi> at Mr. <hi>Samuel Briggs</hi> Scrivener in <hi>Guildhall<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard:</hi> And from half an Hour paſt twelve to half an Hour paſt two every Day at Noon, at <hi>Garraway</hi>'s, <hi>Jonathan</hi>'s, and <hi>Barbadoes</hi> Coffee-houſes in <hi>Exchange-Alley:</hi> At <hi>Batſon</hi>'s and <hi>Bridges</hi> Coffee-houſes in <hi>Cornhill;</hi> and at the <hi>Amſterdam</hi>-Coffee-houſe behind the <hi>Royal Exchange, London.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed by <hi>John Darby</hi> in St. <hi>Bartholomew-Cloſe;</hi> where is ſold Mr. <hi>Briſcoe</hi>'s Book, intituled, <hi>A Diſcourſe on the late Funds, with Propoſals for the Improvement of the Freehold-Eſtates, and Encouragement of Trade.</hi> Price 18 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
